Aleksey Malyavko

Software engineer

Website: https://aleksmalyavko.com/



4+ years of experience

Personal profile

Strong experience in Front-End stack (JavaScript, Vue.js, React.js)

■ Experience in Back-End stack (AEM, Node.js, MongoDB, Express)

Clear understanding of functional and object-oriented programming concepts

Good experience with tools like Figma, Photoshop

■ The desire to develop and learn new things every day

■ Well-organised, friendliness, high attention to detail, problem solver and perfectionist

■ B2 English level (Daily communication with foreign customers)

Core competencies

JavaScript, Vue.js, React.js

Technical skills

Language: JavaScript

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, SASS / SCSS, CSS-in-JS (Styled Components), Svg, Canvas,

JSON, REST, SPA, PWA

JavaScript Libraries & Vue.js, Vuex, Nuxt.js, React.js, RxJS, Redux, Bootstrap, Materialize, Node.js,

Frameworks: Express.js, axios, Webpack, Handlebars.js, Google Maps JS API, Ymaps API,

Mongoose, Lodash, jQuery, Web3.js, Babel, ESLint, Wordpress, Web-components

Package Managers: npm, yarn

Cloud Computing Services Cloudflare Hosting, Heroku Hosting, Firebase Hosting

& Solutions:

Development Tools: Docker, Swagger, Postman, Figma, Fiddler, BrowserStack

Communication & Slack, Skype, Telegram, JIRA, Trello, Discord, Notion

Management Tools:

Version Control System: Git

Education



Economic Cybernetics, BD, 2018 Economic Informatics, MD 2019 Belarusian State Economic University (BSEU)

Professional Experience and projects



Exadel #1:

HP, Z-workstations, HawkSearch, Exadel website

01.06.2018-01.09.2022

Stack: JavaScript, SCSS, Vue, Web-components, AEM, Handlebars, JQuery, Figma, JIRA,

Github, Lodash, Charts.is, WebPack, YouTube API, Docker

Role: Software engineer

Project description: AEM is an admin system for creators and designers which was used for creating

thousands of HP pages with various features and abilities. Z theme of HP (like HyperX, OMEN) part of HP. HawkSearch is a search system for finding different products or pages

connected to a guery. The Exadel website is the main website with lots of content.

Responsibilities: • Creating UI elements\components, simple or hard ones, product finders as searches, sliders with features, spinning 3D objects on scroll, parallax effects, various animations in different states, all components support customizing (color, size, behavior, mode).

- Creating edit mode of components in admin view.
- Implementing UI pages.
- Perfect pixel.
- Responsive and adaptive design.
- RTL support.
- Accessibility support.
- Analytics tracking support.
- Implementing marketing ads.
- Connecting components with various APIs.
- Performance updates.
- SEO.
- Working with the Backend part (AEM, WP).
- Plugin overrides.
- Fix bugs.
- Features implementing.
- Integrate JIRA with Github and set up Jira Automation.
- Write components documentation. Daily meetings with customers, discussion, and gathering requirements.
- Creation and discussion of tasks
- Take part in numerous rallies, including presentations and demos.
- Reviewing the code.
- Troubleshooting.



ITT #2: BiletyPlus

01.02.2018-01.06.2018

Stack: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, GraphQL, JSP, jQuery, Lodash

Role: Software engineer

Project description: A large web application, for searching and selling any kind of tickets for any kind of

transport (plane, bus, train, ferry).

Responsibilities:

Creating UI components.

Implementing UI pages.

Perfect pixel. Responsive and adaptive design.

Implementing marketing ads.

Performance updates.

Working with the Backend part (JAVA).

Fix bugs. Features implementing.

Take part in presentations and demos.

Reviewing the code.

Troubleshooting.



Freelance #3:

Lots of different projects from scratch or existing ones

2017 - present

Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SCSS, Vue, Vuex, Nuxt.js, React, Redux, Web-components,

AEM, Handlebars, JQuery, Lodash, Charts.js, WebPack, Material UI, PWA, SPA,

MongoDB, Node.js, Ymaps API, Google Maps API, Heroku, VK API, Bootstrap, Tailwind,

Figma, JIRA, Github

Role: Frontend developer

Project description: Various projects like tracking systems, analytics and visual app, static sites, medical

appointment app, delivery apps and etc.

Responsibilities: Creating static pages HTML\CSS, components.

Perfect pixel. Responsive and adaptive design.

Implementing analytics. Implementing marketing ads.

■ SEO updates. Performance updates (85-99 score of Google page speed).

Deploying projects on Heroku, Cloudflare.

Working with Backend & Database (Node.js, MongoDB).

Fixing bugs. Plugin overrides. Features implementing.

 Gathering requirements from customers, planning, and troubleshooting. Daily meetings with customers. Take part in presentations and demos.

Reviewing the code.

Fixing bugs.

You can check more here: https://aleksmalyavko.com/#portfolio